Today's topic is going to be very special.
In today's topic, we will talk about a device. It is
very important for you to know that the device is installed in our vehicle
and how it works and what are
its benefits and
what are its drawbacks. So, we will
talk about that device in detail. Its name is
telematics device. You might
not have heard this name before, so we will
get information about it in this video. So
without getting too scared, let's
start the video. Hello friends, my
name is Prabhat Ranjan and you are watching
your own YouTube channel Ustad Ji. So, first of all,
we will talk about what is a telematics device.
Telematics device is an
electronic gadget which is installed inside your vehicle
behind the dashboard or
behind important places. Different brands of
vehicles have it installed in different places.
Why is it installed and
what will be the benefit to the consumer and what will be the benefit to the brand. So, this will
benefit the consumer. The consumer will have a lot of
information collected from this information. After
seeing this information, he can improve his driving.  Behavior can
correct many things and
what will be the benefit to the brand, the brand has
a data
calculated data, after that it will be collected
that which car is running how much, is there a
pattern going on, that is, all the people who are
driving in India, what is their driving pattern, what is their
driving behavior, then it will
try to improve them in the future, that
yes, you are the maximum driver, maximum
car owner who is driving,
what is their driving pattern, what is their
driving behavior, then by keeping that in mind it will
try to reduce it in the future
so that your convenience can be
made better, so now
how is the information shared between the brand and the customer, then we will
talk about it in detail, first of all there is a
small device which is
fitted at the back, that device is a small device, a
SIM is fitted in it, that is the connection
wiring, now from where does it get the information, so there is
a device fitted inside the car
which has all the
electronic sensor parameter
information of the car, the name of that device
can be called electronic control module or electronic control
unit.  You can also say that the vehicle has a
brain, the brain has all the information,
now we understand it in simple language,
this is our body and the brain of our body,
after this it has all the information,
okay and it also decides after seeing,
now but for example, food is
kept in front of me, now whether I should eat the food
or not, it decides whether it is good or
big, my mind, my
eyes saw it, eyes are a sensor, the nose is an
organ, it looks
good too, so my mind will think
that brother, the brain also needs it,
brother, if there is no space in the stomach, then what will happen, the
brain will refuse it, it felt good after seeing it,
but it did
not get activated,
it got information from some sensor through active ind, okay, the
information was fine, it kept it with itself but did
not give any reaction, okay, but
similarly all the information comes after ICM,
okay and the one who gets the information, he
provides it, now if
he is hungry and wants to eat, then to
whom will he give the information, he will give it to his hands, saying
brother, pick it up with your hands and put it in your mouth and then eat it.  It will
give it to you, then chew it and put it
in the stomach, it has been taken in the brain,
after listening and seeing with the eyes, it has been activated by the hands,
because raise your hands and do it, it has
activated the hands, it has
not activated the legs, it knows that
this has to be reduced by the hands, so it
will activate the hands, so the nose and ears are our
sensors which are taking the input,
okay, you are getting the input of smell from the nose,
you are seeing with the eyes,
you are hearing with the ears, so this is the input,
taking this input, it is giving it to the mind i.e. the brain, the
output from the brain, hands, mouth, all these
things are being output, so this is the
method of reducing, information from ECS, ECS
has the information, all the information from PCS,
whatever is required, it is given to the telematic device
because information is required for this thing,
what is the information in it, your RPM,
how are you giving acceleration,
its behavior, brake pattern, is it okay, fuel
consumption, ratio, all this information
of GPS signal, all this information has
gone to the television, you have a
lot of information to the telematic device for getting the information
Then how will the oil reach your phone from the device?
This device will put it on a server cloud.
Cloud is the brand's cloud, the brand has
a cloud in which this information is
stored. The information is sent from the cloud to
your phone. There is a cloud in between,
it will come to the phone. You can see the
current mileage of your car. You
can check your driving disorder health, whether there is any problem with my disorder health, you
can send a service reminder, the
service center will come to you through GPS and tell you the
current location of your car.
Wherever you are, if
someone has taken your car,
you can still see on your phone at
what speed the person driving my car is driving.
You
can track your speed, that is, you
can fix the speed that if the
car goes above this, it will be recorded.
For example, you have given your car to someone, okay friend, if
any friend takes it, you have
fixed a speed for him. If the
car goes above 80, then the information will be sent to him, so
he can call and tell him to drive slowly.  It is
more, okay, he is
not allowed to drive that much speed on the road, he
can be challaned or there may be an accident, so
this is the information, now
why is it necessary to have it installed in the car, it is
important that you firstly want to keep your car
safe from theft, okay, it will
send you a separate message,
if someone opens the car without your keys or
tries to do some tampering with it, then you will get an
alert message, it is
very difficult to disconnect it because it is installed
behind the dashboard, so it consumes a lot of time,
its wiring is also the same, so
disconnecting it is a bit
complicated, so it is
safe as it is, it
helps you in correcting your driving behavior
and there are some
insurance companies which, if a
telematic device is installed in your car, then they
give you some discount in the premium,
now one reason why they give discount is that
you paid the premium, okay, if the
car met with an accident two-three times in a year, then
you have recovered more than the premium you paid,
if you
give the information of the telematic device
to your insurance company, then the insurance company will have the
information about the inside of this car, brother  There
is a telematic device, if
something happens in the future then it will be easy for us to track
that when the owner or
consumer was driving the car, the speed of the car, whether
he was wearing the seat belt or not, what was the
braking pattern, what was the GPS
signal, where did the car meet with an
accident, a lot of information will be
collected after that, so it is
given so that the consumer can also know that
yes, I have given some information to the
company, so I should keep my driving
correct, so if I do something different or do something wrong then there will be
loss, the
company can raise an objection in between that
you are driving at the speed limit because if you are driving at such a high speed on the road, there are
many things which have to be done, there are
many loop
holes in the insurance company, so the insurance company
tries to find a way to
not give a clean chit so that that
time does not come, so you should keep your driving correct, drive
comfortably, drive at a limited speed, whatever the
car is driving at, if it is fine then there will be no
problem, the biggest issue and the
biggest issue is that  The benefit is
of GPS and your driving waiver,
your choice should be helped by the
brand now. Many of these
terminator devices are available from outside only. There are
two reasons for getting them installed from the branch. The first reason is that for
example, you are driving a car, if there is a
malfunction in the car, that
malfunction function is such that you
cannot drive the car, then you will get an alert or a
message because for example, your car is
overheating or the
oil level in the car has gone down. If your car is
overheating or the oil level has gone down, then it will tell
you that brother, the car is overheating,
please stop and whatever is the
authorized dealership near you
which has a G brand car, you should go there and
visit and check it. You did
not see the alert but the car is still running.
After that, it is possible that in 199% of cases, the
brand concern will call the person directly and say
that brother, this is the car's thing,
your car is malfunctioning or the oil is
low, you should take the car to  Just install it, it will
also tell you
which dealerships are near your location, which have authorized
service centers, where you can go and get your vehicle
checked, if no one is there then they will
try their best to provide you road assistance,
so this is also a benefit, now when so much has been
talked about technology, when we have talked about
technology, then when we talk about technology, there
is a threat to private data privacy, that brother, all your information is
on the cloud, it contains all the behavior data of your car, is
that data safe or not,
all your information is there in it, when do you go out,
when do you come in, what is
your driving pattern, how do you drive, so all this has
come under privacy, so big
brands say that they take care of data
security and will do so now
because they have a lot of customers, so
they cannot tamper with the data like this,
so whenever you buy a device in the top model, it
comes by default, you can get it installed in other vehicles,
I don't know about their policy, who
knows, there might be some good companies which
provide security of data, so you should
check the concern condition  What should I say about
data security? If I have to give my data to
someone, then my consent is
necessary first. So, without your consent, no one should
touch your data. So,
these were the benefits and drawbacks
of telematic devices. Now, a telematic device must be going through your mind.
What is a telematic device? So, telematic device is the name
of a feature. Different brands, different companies
sell it by different names. What is its name? For
example, if we talk about a phone, then the phone sells it
by the name of Suzuki Connect.
Honda sells it by the name of Honda Connect.
Hyundai sells it by the name of Blue Link. Kia sells it
by the name of Kia Connect. There are
different brands which
sell it by different names. There may be 1920 variants,
model to variant difference,
but the features are GPS
location, your driving behavior, your
vehicle health, all these will be there. If there is
more, it can start the vehicle a little bit, it will
run it too. If there is
some vehicle, it will run it too.
That means, the more the features are there,
but the
features of the vehicles are these.  All the
basic needs will be available in it, rest you can keep expanding as much as you
want, there is no problem, the
more features you increase, the more privacy will be at
risk, you must have
liked my video, if you liked it then
please subscribe to the channel and
like my video, see you
in the next video, thank you very much